Gamachis Yadesa

Email: gyadesa@gmail.com | 612-481-9934 | Maple Grove, Minnesota

Github: https://github.com/gyadesa |LinkedIn: https://linkedin.com/in/gamachis-yadesa |Portfolio: https://gyadesa.github.io

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Full Stack Web Developer with over 8 years of experience in Software Quality Assurance Life Cycle. Solid history of discovering errors, resolving defects, and ensuring client expectations are met with high quality software solutions. Used Agile methodology to collaborate with developers and project managers to accomplish milestones.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

HTML5/CSS/JavaScript, Bootstrap, jQuery, timers, aJax, Firebase, Nodejs, mySQL, Express, Handlebars, Sequelize, Mocha/Chai, Mongodb, React C#, VB Script, QTP/UFT/Lean FT, Doors, TFS, Git, Jenkins, Agile, Selenium, SVN, Cucumber/SpecFlow.

APPLICATIONS BUILT

Global Sounds (Group Project)

Collaborated and in creating the UI part of the front end

- A web app that allows users to explore global music by API that geocode search of a country or a click on firebase of a map that displays 5 top lists of artists from the searched country.
- Contributed the YouTube search functionality, the embedding of videos using the YouTube API, Firebase, JavaScript, jQuery, and HTML5.
- https://gyadesa.github.io/GlobalSounds/index.html
- https://github.com/gyadesa/projects/tree/master/globalsounds

Memory Game Application (Class work)

React and Heroku, Cloud Platform Use

- React based memory game assignment that requires breaking up applications into UI components,managing component state, and responding to user events.
- Full Stack React developer
- https://github.com/gyadesa/memorystarwars-reactapp
- https://vast-earth-99932.herokuapp.com/

Word Guess Game Application (Class work) Javascript with mysgl database

- A computer word guess game with javascript code. Runs on a browser that listens to a key events that a player types and the user has to guess which word the app chose.
- Full Stack developer
- https://gyadesa.github.io/wordGuessGame/index.html
- https://github.com/gyadesa/projects/tree/master/wordGuessGame-JavaScript

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

YBS Solutions, LLC.(Maple Grove, MN St. Paul)

October 2017- Current

Web Developer

- Complete digital projects sorting algorithms that updated in real-time as new filter parameters were selected; JavaScript developer on the project.
- Develop a dynamic driven solutions database using JavaScript; increased user clicks by 65%.

Baxter Healthcare (Brooklyn Park, MN)

July 2017 – October 2017

Senior Software Verification and Validation Engineer (Consultant)

- Performed system verification and test validation process of dialysis infusion systems.
- Reviewed verification and validation test cases and software test documentation.
- Designed test plans and test cases for Dialysis therapeutic renal care system.
- Carried out simulator test scripts using Python programming language.
- Used HP ALM and DOORS for Software Test application planning and documentation.
- Reported defects, test reviews and test results using JIRA bug management system.

Gamachis Yadesa

Smiths Medical (Plymouth, MN)

May 2014 - June 2017

Senior Software Automation Engineer (Consultant)

- Led test team with daily scrum and Agile process using Ms Team Foundation (FTS).
- Designed and developed of PharmGuard (Health Care Management System) automation.
- Gained working knowledge of automation frameworks such as SpecFlow UFT and LeanFT.
- Conducted continuous automation test integration, delivery and reported daily build results.
- Updated daily smoke test codes were current and up-to-date with daily application changes.
- Supported SSIS, SMO and CLR components of the SQL Server components for reports.

Smiths Medical (St. Paul, MN)

July 2012 – April 2014

Software Test Engineer (Consultant)

- Evaluated product requirements and outlined specifications.
- Linked requirements to validation protocols using IBM requirement tracking tool (Doors).
- Prepared validation plan based on requirements for medical drug infusion device.
- Oversaw teamwork and assigned different testing tasks.
- Worked with on-and off-site quality assurance teams to coordinate testing.
- Continuously updated testing documentation.
- Provided QA feedback for review retrospectives.
- Supported and complied with FDA regulations (510(k)) in all R&D testing.

Fluke Thermography (Plymouth, MN)

January 2011 – January 2012

Software Test Engineer (Consultant)

- Responsible for designing test cases and scenarios for usability testing.
- Updated testing documentation for new hires.
- Received and interpreted product owner specifications.
- Performed compatibility and continues improvement of legacy product testing.
- Tested a leading-edge thermograph imager and supported software application tool.
- Generated and analyzed resultant radiometric sounds, videos, and standard image files.

Smiths Medical (St. Paul, MN)

August 2008 - December 2011

Firmware Verification and Validation Engineer (Consultant)

- Performed Embedded Software Testing, Verification and Validation of drug infusion medical device with the integration of SDLS/STLC and applying principles of FDA regulations.
- Calibrated and tested hardware and firmware of a medical drug infusion device.
- Installed embedded software releases and performed white box tests.
- Wrote and maintained SQL scripts for data transfer and analysis from the device to a server.
- Validated both cable and wireless (802.11 b/g) data transfers; S-HTTP and SSL protocols.

EDUCATION

University of Minnesota (St. Paul, MN)

May 2018 - Present

Full-stack Flex Coding Boot camp - Javascript Full Stack Web Development in intensive 24-week long boot camp dedicated to designing and building web applications. Node.Js, Express, JavaScript, jQuery, React.js, React Native, GIT, Github, MongoDB, MySQL, Firebase, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Media Queries, APIs, JSON, REST, AJAX, the command line, computer science fundamentals, writing tests.

University of St. Thomas (St. Paul, MN)

Master of Science, Software Engineering and Database Management

Minnesota State University (Mankato, MN)

Bachelor of Science, Computer Information Systems and Software Management Systems